welcome back to another video editing
欢迎回到另一个视频编辑
tutorial in the free software kdenlive
免费软件kdenlive的教程
in this video we're going to be looking
在这段视频中 我们将看到
at the crop and transform effects so
在裁剪和变换效果上如此
that we can change the look of our video
我们可以改变视频的外观
basically we can zoom in and just watch
基本上我们可以放大然后看着
one portion of our video like the top
我们视频的一部分就像上图
right hand corner we can zoom out we can
右上角我们可以缩小我们可以
drag and move the video around to a
将视频拖动并移动到
different location to get started I'm
从不同的地方开始 我是
going to read in a video clip I'll just
我要读一段视频剪辑 我只想
click up here on my add clip and I can
点击我的添加剪辑这里 我就可以
find a nice clip here of this cyclist
在这里找到这个骑自行车的人的一个不错的剪辑
that we've used in the past so if we
我们过去用过的 所以如果我们
play this it just shows us here's the
播放这个 它只是向我们展示了这是
cyclist grabbing his bike but maybe we
骑自行车的人抓住了他的自行车 但也许我们
want to zoom in and only be we don't
想要放大 只是我们不想
want to see these bikes over here we
想看看我们这边的这些自行车吗
don't like the way that shot looks so we
我不喜欢那张照片的样子 所以我们
can just zoom in and just see this
我可以把它放大就能看到这个
portion here there's a couple ways we
这里有几种方法我们可以
can do it but first let's left-click and
我可以做到 但首先让我们左键单击并
drag this down to our video track 1 so
把这个拖到我们的视频轨道1上 这样
we have our video here and I'm gonna go
我们有我们的视频 我要走了
to the bottom right and zoom in so we
放到右下角 然后放大 这样我们
can kind of see art a little bit larger
我可以把艺术看得更大一点
view of our timeline and now we can see
查看我们的时间线 现在我们可以看到
what this looks like I'm gonna left
这看起来像什么 我要离开
click on the playhead and just hold and
点击播放头 然后按住并
drag until I get to the point so I can
拖到我要找的地方 这样我就可以
kind of see so the camera does move a
可以看到 摄像机确实移动了
little bit that doesn't really matter
一点都不重要
let's just for all intents and purposes
让我们只是出于所有的意图和目的
let's just cut in maybe like where his
我们就直接切入吧 也许就像他
knees are and have the video be kind of
膝盖是 让视频有点像
this portion here so we need to apply a
这一部分 因此我们需要应用一个
crop effect so we could just type in
裁剪效果 这样我们就可以只输入
crop up here actually it's not really
突然出现在这里实际上它并不是真的
crop what we want to do even though the
裁剪我们想要做的事情 即使
effect is called crop it's under the
效果被称为作物 它是在
transform effect so we're gonna left
变形特效所以我们要离开
click on transform and drag it down into
单击Transform并将其向下拖动到
here and then we see we have the options
我们时不时地看到 我们有选择
appear under these properties and we can
出现在这些属性下 我们可以
have different in the last video we did
在上一个视频中有不同
this speed under motion with speed and
这个速度随着速度和速度一起运动
we can actually apply multiple effects
我们实际上可以应用多种效果
to one single clip so right now we have
到一个单独的剪辑 所以现在我们有
speed here and we have transform and
速度在这里 我们有转变和
this little triangle which toggles which
这个小三角形可以切换到
one we're viewing we can be both at the
我们正在观看的一部电影我们可以同时在
same time speed only has one setting to
同一时间速度只有一个设置为
change I'm going to delete it though and
更改我要删除它 然后
but this transform effect has multiple
但这种变换效果有多个
different settings so what for example
不同的设置 例如
we can do the biggest thing by default
我们可以默认做最大的事情
there's maybe size so we can come here
可能有尺寸 这样我们就可以来这里了
and change the size the size just like
并改变大小 就像
we did with speed we
我们用我们的速度做到了
change the size at 200% and hit enter
将大小更改为200% 然后按Enter键
and then it zooms in 200% based off of
然后它会放大200% 基于
the top left-hand corner we can then
然后我们可以在左上角
change like this X&Y issues our scroll
像这样的变化X&Y发行我们的卷轴
wheel and change like slowly it's moving
轮子和变化 就像它在缓慢地移动
over a pixel-by-pixel or we can type in
一个像素接一个像素 或者我们可以输入
like negative 300 and it'll move over on
如果是负300 它就会往下移动
the x-axis that much but what we can
X轴那么多 但我们能做的是
also do I'm gonna reset this back to how
另外 我要把这件事重新设置为
it was I'll click these three lines here
我会在这里点击这三行
and go to reset effect and that just
然后转到Reset Effect 然后
resets everything back to how it was
将一切重置为原来的样子
before we made any changes another way
在我们以另一种方式做出任何改变之前
we can move it around just by clicking
我们只需点击鼠标即可将其移动
here there's a little dot in the center
这里中间有一个小圆点
we can left-click and then we can move
我们可以左键点击 然后我们就可以移动
this video to any place we want if we
这段视频到任何我们想去的地方如果我们
play the video it'll just play from
播放它将从其开始播放的视频
right there so it's actually playing
就在那里 所以它实际上正在播放
just has some black lines up here we can
只是在这里有一些黑线 我们可以
resize so if we go to the edge we can
调整大小 这样如果我们走到边缘 我们就可以
actually resize this and it's going to
实际上调整这个大小 它将会
resize it uniformly because we have this
统一调整大小 因为我们有这个
little link checked here keep lock
选中此处的小链接保持锁定
aspect ratio so our width is now 602 and
纵横比现在我们的宽度是602
our height is now 339 we see those
我们现在的身高是339我们看到了那些
numbers change as we move this the size
随着我们移动这个大小 数字会发生变化
changes so now it's 52% so that's
变化了 所以现在是52% 所以
another way we can change it we can come
我们可以用另一种方式改变它 我们可以来
over here to the percentage and just
在这里计算百分比 然后
scroll wheel up and down and change it
上下滚动滚轮并更改它
we can do these different handles or
我们可以做这些不同的手柄 或者
these different dots on the corner and
角上的这些不同的点和
move it around that a change of size
移动它 改变它的大小
that way and because I'm moving around
这样的话 因为我在四处走动
so those are the it's kind of cool the
所以这些都是很酷的
different ways we have of changing this
我们有不同的方式来改变这一点
video but yeah if we want to go in and
录像带 但如果我们想进去
that's why it's kind of nice sometimes
这就是为什么有时天气很好的原因
use these numbers because if we actually
使用这些数字是因为如果我们实际上
want to zoom in like greater than 100%
我想要放大到100%以上
we start to lose that Center that Center
我们开始失去那个中心那个中心
dot we don't know exactly where it is so
我们不知道它的确切位置 所以
it's good it gets harder to move around
很好 走动变得更困难了
especially if we're in at like 300% then
尤其是如果我们是300%的话
it's hard to see so that's why it's nice
它很难看到 所以这就是为什么它很好
to use the X&Y in that case sometimes so
在这种情况下使用X&Y有时是这样
we might go negative 204 here or maybe
我们可能会在这里变成负204 或者
let's just go back to 0 and maybe that's
让我们回到0 也许那是
too much let's go to 200 on this ok so
太多了 我们赌200美元 好吗？
now we can kind of see here but we can
现在我们可以在这里看到 但我们可以
barely see that little dot so we'll
几乎看不到那个小点 所以我们
bring it over to there so now let's play
把它拿到那里来 现在我们来玩吧
this we can go back to the beginning or
这个我们可以回到起点 或者
roughly the beginning and we can play
大概一开始 我们就可以玩
and see he's grabbing the bike
看 他正在抓起自行车
going and if we want to see what this
如果我们想看看这是什么
looks like compared to the original
看起来像是和原来的
video we still have it over here in our
视频我们仍然把它放在我们的
project bin we can click on clip monitor
我们可以点击剪辑监视器上的项目栏
and we can see what it looks like there
我们可以看到那里是什么样子
so here is this is what our project
这就是我们的项目
looks like and in the clip monitor this
看起来是这样的 在剪辑监视器中
is what the original shot looked like so
原来的照片看起来是这样的
we can see how far in we are how far
我们可以看到我们在多远的地方
cropped in we are yeah
我们被裁剪了 是的
that's basically it there's also
基本上就是这样 还有
rotation so if we go back to a project
轮换 所以如果我们回到一个项目
monitor we can also rotate this shot so
监视器 我们还可以旋转这张照片
we probably this is pretty level if I
我们可能这是相当水平的 如果我
wouldn't want to but we could rotate it
我不想 但我们可以轮换
a tiny bit and we just click and now
一点点 我们只需点击一下 现在
it's rotated but we have until we see a
它是旋转的 但我们有 直到我们看到一个
black line there so if we did rotation
那里有一条黑线 所以如果我们旋转
we want to move this up to maybe like
我们想把这个升级到像这样
you know a certain point because what's
你知道某一点 因为什么是
happening is as we zoom out here it's
当我们把镜头拉到这里的时候
actually just rotating the whole thing
实际上只是旋转整个过程
so we get some black appearing and so
所以我们看到一些黑色的出现 所以
depending on what you're doing rotation
根据您所做的轮换
is an option yeah that is the basically
是一种选择吗？是的 这基本上就是
that's the effect for transform there's
这就是转型的效果
some different ones if we want to delete
如果我们想要删除一些不同的
this effect it goes back to normal
这种效果会恢复到正常状态
we've got letterbox we can just drag in
我们有信箱 我们可以直接拖进去
and that just has black bars on the top
上面只有黑条
and the bottom we can change the size of
我们可以改变底部的大小
it so if you want to create the kind
如果你想创造一种
like a cinematic effect have an ultra
就像电影效果一样有一种极端的
wide screen it'll still export the video
宽屏仍将输出视频
1920 by 1080 or whatever your settings
1920 x 1080或您的任何设置
are but it'll export it with a black box
但它会将其与黑盒一起输出
like this it's like a letter boxing and
就像这样 它就像一个字母拳击
it just kind of helps draw your eyes to
它只是在某种程度上帮助你吸引眼球
like a certain portion of the video so
喜欢视频的某一部分 所以
it's letterboxing an edge crop kind of
这是一种边缘作物的信箱
does the same thing I'll just show you a
做同样的事情 我会给你们展示一个
few of these with edge crop if we drag
如果我们拖动 很少会有边缘裁剪
it in we can crop just a certain edge so
在它里面 我们可以只裁剪一个特定的边缘
from the right we can crop in a little
从右边开始 我们可以稍微裁剪一下
bit so it cuts out part of the right and
这样它就切掉了一部分右手边
then it also is centering the it Reese
那么它也是以它为中心的
enters the video but it cut out part so
进入了视频 但它剪掉了一部分
that's another way we could do it if we
这是我们可以做的另一种方式 如果我们
want to cut out those bikes over there
想把那边的那些自行车剪掉吗？
we can just do this so that cuts out
我们可以这样做 这样就可以切断
those bikes and but then it still shows
那些自行车 但它仍然显示
this portion of the video so we can
视频的这一部分 以便我们可以
watch and see yeah what that looks like
看吧 看看那是什么样子的
and then again just like in the other
然后再一次 就像另一个一样
tutorials we can render this out save it
我们可以将其渲染出来的教程保存它
to a certain place on the computer I'm
到电脑上的某个地方 我正在
not going to do it here but you get the
不会在这里做 但你会得到
idea
理念
and there's some of these with things
还有一些这样的东西
have key or keyframe well we'll talk
有关键字或关键帧好的 我们会谈的
about keyframes and future tutorials but
关于关键帧和未来教程 但
what that lets us do is actually apply
这让我们可以实际应用
if we wanted to do a good example might
如果我们想做一个好的例子 也许
be this letterboxing if we want to
如果我们想的话就做这个信箱吧
keyframe the letterboxing which I don't
为我不喜欢的信箱打关键帧
know if it even lets us do but it would
我知道它是否允许我们这样做 但它会的
be animated so it would like slowly we
让它动起来 这样它就会慢慢地像我们
would see this part moving as the video
会看到这一部分随着视频而移动
is also moving whereas right now
也在移动 而现在
whatever we set it to it stays that way
不管我们给它设置什么 它都会保持原样
that's how we could like zoom in on the
这就是我们想要放大的
shot while the shot is actually playing
在实际播放快照时进行拍摄
is by using keyframes and again check
是通过使用关键帧并再次选中
out future tutorials where we learn how
在未来的教程中 我们将了解如何
to do that appreciate you watching this
感谢您收看这期节目
video go ahead and like comment
视频继续 喜欢评论
subscribe get involved in the
订阅参与
conversation leave comments below of
对话在下面留下评论
types of videos you'd like me to make or
你想让我做的视频类型
if you want to learn a specific thing
如果你想学习一个特定的东西
that I'm not covering I'd love to hear
我想听听
from you
从你
but yeah appreciate your watching and
但是的 谢谢你的观看
I'll catch you in the next video
下一段视频里我们会看到